Guide to the Pierce and Bickford records,1890-1960.
Pierce and Bickford records
- Job file drawings (Box 133-148)
  - Elmira, NY
    - Booth, I. D., warehouse (Box 136)
      Job# 1098
    - Brady Electric Building (Box 134)
      Job# 432 1/2
    - Brand, J. Herbert, residence (Box 142)
      Job# 1442
    - Call, Mr., residence (Box 134)
      Job# 601
    - Centenary Methodist Episcopal Church (Box 145)
      Job# 1584
    - Century Club (Box 135)
      Job# 1008
    - City Hall (Folder 25-28)
      Job# 385, 582, 1144, 1148
    - Chemung Company Building (Box 134)
      Job# 517
    - Christ's United Methodist Church (Box 144)
      Job# 1464, 1583
    - Clinton, A., residence (Box 134)
      Job# 611
    - Copley, Hovey (Box 134)
      Job# 559
    - Country Club (Box 136)
      Job# 1124
    - Cross, C.J., residence (Box 134)
      Job# 475
    - Curtis, George L. Company, Warehouse Strengthening (Box 140)
      Job# 1560 1/2 (with Job# 1327)
    - Curtis, George L. Company, Wholesale Grocery Building (Box 140)
      Job# 1327
    - Curtis, George L. Company, Warehouse (Box 141)
      Job# 1375
    - Davenport, E.R., residence (Box 136)
      Job# 1108
    - Dean, Mr. Elmer, apartment house (Box 144)
      Job# 1582
    - Decker, Casper G., residence (Box 137)
      Job# 1130
    - Dunn, E.J., Building (Box 142)
      Job# 1493
    - Elmira City Club, 1892-1919 (Folder 6)
      Job# 796
      Basement Plan, First Floor Plan
      Second Floor Plan
      Longitudinal Section
      Church Street Elevation
      Lake Street Elevation
      South Elevation
      Rear Elevation
      Full size detail of mantel for Banquet Room
      Detail of New Doors and Changes in Pantry
    - Elmira City Club, alterations, 1938-1945 (Folder 6)
      Job# 1641
      Stair Details
      Alteration Second Floor
      Alteration Details of Wood Stairs and Railing
      Proposed Basement Plan, Robert T. Bickford
      Blueprint of Basement Plan
      Sewer lines from Janowski
      Hand drawn diagrams on graph for heating system, undated
    - Elmira, City of, Municipal Garage (Box 141)
      Job# 1411
    - Elmira Free Academy (Box 138)
      Job# 1196
    - Elmira Silk Company (Box 134)
    - Elmira Water Board (Box 147)
      Job# 1741, 1777
    - Emblem, L. H., residence (formerly the Ed. Roe residence) (Box 136)
      Job# 1069
    - Ferguson Building (Folder 12)
      Job# 1017A
    - Ferguson, W.H., residence (Box 134)
      Job# 448
    - Ferguson, W.H., stores, 1908-1909 (Folder 12)
      Job# 1017
    - Fire Station No. 4, 1897 (Folder 5)
      Job# 671
      Foundation Plan, First Floor Plan
      Front Elevation
      Right Side Elevation
      Left Side Elevation
      First Floor Framing Plan
      Second Floor Framing Plan
      Roof Framing Plan
      Plan of Stall Floor
      Spacing for Supports of Railing over Sitting Room. Drawings scale 1/4"
    - First Baptist Church (Box 133)
      Job# 53
    - Friendly, residence, W. Church (also known as the Hedding Parsonage) (Folder 1)
      Job# 17
    - Friendly, Sam., residence (Box 133)
      Job# 34
    - Gray, Dr. J. (Box 146)
      Job# 1723
    - Hedding Methodist Episcopal Church (See also Job# 1583, Christ's United Methodist Church), 1899 (Folder 19-21)
      Job# 724
    - Hoffman, Allyn, residence (Box 143)
      Job# 1557
    - Home for the Aged (Box 148)
      Job# 1771
    - Howell, F.M., (John Brand) (Box 133)
      Job# 20
    - Jarvis, George T., residence (Box 147)
      Job# 1756
    - Kelly Electric Company (S. Bednarer) (Box 148)
      Job# 1763
    - Lake St. Presbyterian Church (Box 133)
      Job# 63
    - Langdon, Miss Ida, residence (Box 145)
      Job# 1642
    - Langdon, Mrs. C.J., residence, 1904 (Folder 9)
      Job# 941
    - Library (Box 134)
      Job# 738
    - Marks, M. Doyle (Box 143)
      Job# 1568 1/2
    - Markthaler, T.H., residence, 1904 (Folder 8)
      Job# 910
    - Masonic Temple (Box 136)
      Job# 1117
    - Masonic Temple (Box 140)
      Job# 1291
    - McDowell, R.P., residence (Box 143)
      Job# 1566
    - Moody, Mr., residence (Box 134)
    - Morrow, A.P., residence (Box 134)
    - Morrow, A.P., residence (Box 135)
      Job# 836
    - N.Y. Telephone Company (Box 148)
      Job# 1767 (with Job# 1772-E)
    - N.Y. Telephone Company (Box 148)
      Job# 1772-E
    - NYS N.G. Armory (Folder 2)
      Job# 58
    - Parsons, Mrs. F.W., residence (Box 135)
      Job# 981
    - Pickering, G., 368 W. Church (Box 133)
      Job# 48
    - Post Office Building (Box 145)
      Job# 1687
    - Federation Pharmacy (formerly Railroad YMCA) (Box 133)
      Job# 68
    - Rathbone Corp., garage (Box 142)
      Job# 1531
    - Reynolds, Mrs. J.A., garage (Box 136)
      Job# 1090
    - Riggs, G., residence (Box 133)
      Job# 24
    - Riverside Methodist Episcopal Church (Box 140)
      Job# 575, 1295
    - Romer, A., residence, College Ave. (Box 133)
      Job# 16
    - Rorick's Glen, bridge approach (Box 138)
      Job# 1030 A-N, P (with Job #1217)
    - Roricks Glen Restaurant (Box 138)
      Job# 1217
    - Roricks Glen Theatre (Box 138)
      Job# 932 (with Job #1217)
    - Rosenfield, M., residence (Box 135)
      Job# 975
    - Roverts & Sons, casket factory (Box 137)
      Job# 1175
    - School No.4 (Box 134)
      Job# 798
    - Second National Bank (Box 143)
      Job# 1568
    - Sheriff's & District Attorney's offices (Box 134)
      Job# 747
    - Shoemaker, Guy W., buildings (Box 134)
      Job# 659,660
    - St. Patrick's Church, 1914 (Folder 17)
      Job# 1290
    - St. Patrick's Church (Box 137)
      Job# 1160 1/2
    - St. Patrick's School, 1892 (Folder 3)
      Job# 435
    - St. Peter's & St. Paul's Church (Box 133)
      Job# 42
    - Telegram Building (Brooks, High School) (Box 139)
      Job# 1258
    - Thatcher Manufacturing Company (Box 145)
      Job# 1665,1666
    - Tompkins, C.M. & R., Store Building (Box 133)
      Job# 21
    - Tompkins, Fassett, & Crocker (Box 133)
      Job# 239
    - Trinity Church Rectory (Box 138)
      Job# 1232
    - Tuberculosis Hospital (Box 136)
      Job# 1125
    - Turner, R.T., Esq., 219-221 West Water Street, 1909 (Folder 13)
      Job# 1146
      First Floor Plan
      Front and Rear Elevation
      Details of Bay Window
    - Turner, R.T., Estate, 1928 (Folder 13)
      Job# 1578
    - Walsh, Robert, residence (Box 138)
      Job# 1200
    - Wantuk, M.L., residence (Box 148)
      Job# 1764 1/2
    - Warner, F. A., Church St. (Box 134)
      Job# 519
    - Welles, Gillett, Jr., residence (Box 145)
      Job# 1652
    - Welm Radio Studios (Box 148)
      Job# 1791
    - Wheadon, C.F., residence (Box 135)
      Job# 1016
    - Women's Federation Building (Box 133)
      Job# 61
    - Wood, G. M., residence (Box 134)
      Job# 526
    - Woodlawn Cemetery (Box 135)
      Job# 961
    - Woodlawn Cemetery (Box 133)
      Job# 265
    - Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) (Box 143)
      Job# 1538
    - Zeiser-Wilbur Vault Company (Box 147)
      Job# 1740
  - Elmira Heights - Whitney Point, NY
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 136)
      Eldridge Park
      Job# 572
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 145)
      Elmira Heights High School
      Job# 1585
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 141)
      Yarn Mill
      Job# 719 (with Job #1380)
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 141)
      Elmira Knitting Mills
      Job# 633,755 (with Job# 1380)
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 141)
      Job# 1012 (with Job# 1380)
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 141)
      Elmira Knitting Mills, bdg. house
      Job# 1060 (with Job# 1380)
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 141)
      Job# 1140 (with Job# 1380)
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 141)
      Job# 1273 (with Job# 1380)
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 141)
      Job# 1350,1353,1379 1/2,1380,1383 1/2,
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 145)
      Grade School Building
      Job# 1586
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 141)
      Oakwod Avenue Methodist Episcopal Church
      Job# 1359
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 140)
      Job# 1300
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 143)
      Dept. Building
      Job# 632 (with Job #1558)
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 143)
      Town Hall
      Job# 1558
    - Elmira Heights, NY (Box 143)
      Job# 1170 and 1170 1/2 (with Job#1557)
    - Falconer, NY (Box 138)
      Falconer School
      Job# 1226
    - Falconer, NY (Box 139)
      First National Bank Building
      Job# 1271
    - Friendship, NY (Box 136)
      Friendship School
      Job# 1079
    - Geneva, NY, 1894 (Folder 4)
      Smith's Office Building
      Job# 547
      Terra Cotta Spandrel, "Smith's Opera House" Arch details, 1894
      Arch but with less details and with Cross Section of masonry, 1/4" scale Elevation of Section
      Columns & Beams, Basement Comm. Building - Foundation Plan
      First Floor Plan - Comm. Building
      Second Floor Plan - Comm. Building
      Third Floor Plan - Comm. Building
      Roof Plan - Comm. Building,
      Front Elevation - Comm. Building(Poster made from this front of building)
      Third Floor Framing - Steelwork Comm. Building
      Second Floor Framing - Steelwork Comm. Building
      First Floor Framing Steelwork Comm. Building
      Longitudinal Section Through Center of Building Looking East Comm. Building
      Section of Stairs Showing Front of Opera House
      Opera House Roof Line "Looking North" Comm. Building
      Same But Looking South. Rear Wall of Comm.
      Building Shown "Looking South" Comm. Building
      West Side Elevation (Left) - West Wall Comm. Building
      East Side Elevation (Right) - East Wall Comm. Building
    - Geneva, NY, 1894 (Folder 4)
      Smith Opera House
      Job# 547 1/2
      Elevation of House Right Boxes and Elevation of Proscenium
      West Side Elevation
      East Side Elevation
      Front and Rear Elevations
      Attic Plan
      Third Floor Plan (Structural)
      Second Floor Plan (Structural)
      First Floor Plan (Structural)
      Stage Plan & Stage Elevation
      Roof Plan
      Third Floor Plan
    - Geneva, NY, 1902-1904 (Folder 7)
      YMCA Building
      Job# 841
    - Geneva, NY (Box 133)
      Job# 428
    - Greene, NY (Box 134)
      Job# 823
    - Homer, NY (Box 137)
      Old Ladies Home
      Job# 1128
    - Hornell, NY (Box 142)
      Hornell Court House
      Job# 1053 (with Job# 1527)
    - Hornell, NY (Box 145)
      Huguet Silk Company, Dye House
      Job# 1598
    - Hornell, NY (Box 139)
      Presbyterian Church, addition
      Job# 1250
    - Hornell, NY (Box 142)
      Steuben Sanitarium
      Job# 1527
    - Horseheads, NY (Box 133)
      Fire Dept.
      Job# 432
    - Horseheads, NY (Box 133)
      Horseheads school
      Job# 298
    - Horseheads, NY (Box 133)
      M. E. Church
      Job# 44
    - Horseheads, NY (Box 133)
      Job# 43
    - Lakemont, NY (Box 143)
      Aged Ministers Home
      Job# 1536
    - Lakemont, NY (Box 134)
      Starkey Seminary
      Job# 730,734
    - Lakemont, NY (Box 143)
      Job# 1560
    - Lakemont, NY (Box 143)
      Starkey Seminary sheds
      Job# 812 (with Job# 1560)
    - Lima, NY (Box 137)
      Genesee Wesleyan Seminary
      Job# 1141
    - Manchester, NY (Box 140)
      Job# 1297
    - Millport, NY (Box 145)
      Grade School
      Job# 1596
    - Montour Falls, NY (Box 147)
      Baker, Roland, residence
      Job# 1744
    - Montour Falls, NY (Box 138)
      Shepard Electric Crane & Hoist Company
      Job# 1192
    - Montour Falls, NY (Box 141)
      Job# 1362-1366
    - Montour Falls, NY (Box 144)
      Turner, Robert T., residence
      Job# 1574
    - Montour Falls, NY (Box 144)
      Cook Academy Gym
      Job# 1579
    - Morris, NY (Box 145)
      Linn Manufacturing Company
      Job# 1672
    - Newark Valley, NY (Box 141)
      Methodist Episcopal Church
      Job# 1374
    - Odessa, NY (Box 148)
      German, Mr. & Mrs. Robert., residence
      Job# 1780
    - Olean, NY (Box 134)
      Olean School #2
      Job# 620
    - Owego, NY (Folder 22-23)
      Job# 1005
    - Owego, NY (Box 148)
      Tioga County Historical Society Museum
      Job# 1779
    - Owego, NY (Folder 24)
      Tioga County Clerk's Office
      Job# 1007
    - Painted Post, NY (Box 140)
      Job# 1316
    - Painted Post, NY (Box 134)
      Job# 689
    - Painted Post, NY (Box 142)
      Town Hall Building
      Job# 1449
    - Penn Yan, NY (Box 141)
      Chestnut St. School
      Job# 1435
    - Penn Yan, NY (Box 143)
      Hutton St. School
      Job# 1534, 1535
    - Penn Yan, NY (Box 133)
      Penn Yan School
      Job# 376
    - Penn Yan, NY (Box 133)
      Yates County Surrogates Office
      Job# 49
    - Penn Yan, NY (Folder 18)
      Yates County House, Additions and Alterations, August 1922
      Job# 1508
      Floor plans before additions & alterations
      Additions & alterations
      Sewage disposal plant
      Map of grounds
    - Plattsburgh, NY (Box 135)
      Hospital
      Job# 895
    - Reading Center, NY (Box 142)
      Raymond Free Library, Public
      Job# 1486
    - Spencer, NY, 1927 (Folder 10)
      Job# 947
      Layout of Sewage disposal
      Basement plan showing new toilets
      Details of toilet stalls
    - Spencer, NY, 1905 (Folder 11)
      Job# 948
    - Warsaw, NY (Box 139)
      High School Annex
      Job# 1277
    - Warwick, NY (Box 134)
      Job# 468
    - Waterloo, NY (Box 141)
      St. Paul's Rectory
    - Watkins Glen, NY (Box 145)
      Job# 1605.2
    - Waverly, NY (Box 142)
      First National Bank
      Job# 1443
    - Waverly, NY (Box 133)
      Mills & O'Brien, Bottling Works
      Job# 361
    - Waverly, NY (Box 136)
      National Protective Legion Building
      Job# 1068 (includes Job# 832)
    - Waverly, NY (Box 144)
      Waverly School
      Job# 1572
    - Wellsville, NY (Box 142)
      Anderson, Miss Katherine, residence
      Job# 1454
    - Wellsville, NY (Box 137)
      Country Club
      Job# 1188
    - Wellsville, NY (Box 137)
      Grammar School
      Job# 1154
    - Wellsville, NY (Box 137)
      Job# 1147
    - Wellsville, NY (Box 141)
      Kerr Turbine Company
      Job# 1331
    - Wellsville, NY (Box 139)
      Job# 1241
    - Wellsville, NY (Box 136)
      St. Johns Episcopal Chapel
      Job# 1093
    - Whitney Point, NY (Box 134)
      Job# 787
  - Athens-Wyalusing, PA
    - Athens, PA (Box 133)
      Job# 40
    - Blossburg, PA (Box 133)
      Job# 273
    - Bradford, PA (Box 139)
      Job# 1285
    - Bradford, PA (Box 139)
      Job# 1284
    - Bradford, PA (Box 134)
      Job# 688
    - Canton, PA (Box 145)
      First National Bank of Canton
    - Canton, PA (Box 135)
      Innis, John, residence
      Job# 917
    - Canton, PA (Box 134)
      Job# 481
    - Elkland, PA (Box 134)
      Elkland School
      Job# 799
    - Elkland, PA (Box 140)
      Proctor, Ellison & Company, hide hse.
      Job# 1320
    - Kane, McKean County, PA (Box 133)
      Congregational Society
      Job# 18
    - Knoxville, PA (Box 134)
      City Club Roof Garden
      Job# 788
    - Mansfield, PA (Box 138)
      Mansfield Library (Carnegie)
      Job# 1201
    - Mansfield, PA (Box 136)
      Mansfield Normal School
      Job# 1070, A
    - Mansfield, PA (Box 141)
      Mansfield Normal School (Model School Building)
      Job# 1240, 1410
    - Mansfield, PA (Box 143)
      Mansfield Presbyterian Church
      Job# 1563
    - Roseville, PA (Box 142)
      Alterations to Methodist Episcopal Church
      Job# 1474
    - Sayre, PA (Box 141)
      East Side School Building
      Job# 1341
    - Sayre, PA (Box 140)
      Elmer Ave. School
      Job# 1308
    - Sayre, PA (Box 133)
      Job# 363
    - Sayre, PA (Box 136)
      Job# 1094
    - Sayre, PA (Box 136)
      Packer Hospital
      Job# 1091
    - Sayre, PA (Box 134)
      Job# 512
    - Sayre, PA (Box 136)
      Sayre Town Hall
      Job# 1025
    - Tidionte, PA (Box 134)
      Job# 438
    - Towanda, PA (Box 140)
      High & Grade School
      Job# 1305
    - Towanda, PA (Box 141)
      Job# 1328
    - Towanda, PA (Box 141)
      Towanda Electric Illuminating Company
    - Troy, PA (Box 147)
      Martha Lloyd School
      Job# 1757
    - Troy, PA (Box 146)
      Parsons, Jack, residence
      Job# 1712
    - Ulster, Bradford County, PA (Box 133)
      Presbyterian Society
      Job# 19
    - Wellsboro, PA (Box 139)
      Job# 1288
    - Wellsboro, PA (Box 148)
      Calderhead, R.J., residence
      Job# 1768
    - Westfield, PA (Box 145)
      Eberle, J.F., Tannery
      Job# 1324,1325 (with Job# 1595)
    - Westfield, PA (Box 145)
      Job# 1329 (with Job# 1595)
    - Westfield, PA (Box 145)
      Eberle, J.F., Tannery (also referred to as the factory Building)
      Job# 1174 (with Job# 1595)
    - Westfield, PA (Box 145)
      Eberle Tanning Company
      Job# 1319 (with Job# 1595)
    - Westfield, PA (Box 145)
      Job# 1423 (with Job# 1595)
    - Westfield, PA (Box 145)
      Job# 1450,1473 (with Job# 1595)
    - Westfield, PA (Box 145)
      Job# 1595
    - Westfield, PA (Box 146)
      Job# 1718
    - Westfield, PA (Box 141)
      Farmers' & Traders' National Bank
      Job# 1378
    - Westfield, PA (Box 133)
      Job# 10
    - Westfield, PA (Box 135)
      Job# 867
    - Westfield, PA (Box 139)
      Job# 1261
    - Wyalusing, PA (Box 133)
      Job# 12
- Recent correspondence, Bickford genealogy, photographs, printed material (Box 149)
- Job Index, Photographs, Cartoons etc. (Box 150)
  2 vol. "Job Index": Vol. I Jobs 1-1612; Vol. I1 Jobs 1613-1792
  Photographs of schools and banks
  Scattered newspaper articles,1909,1911,1950's-1966
  Cartoons of H. H. Bickford and J. H. Pierce by Zim (?)
  Map of Chemung County,1911
  Plan of Elmira College campus (undated).
- Glass slides, Printing blocks, Glass plate negatives, etc.
  - Glass slides and printing blocks, Undated (Box 132)
    Contains the wood block of Clifton Springs Sanitarium (see prints in Box 143)
  - Glass plate negatives, Undated (Box 151)
  - Ledger with list of photographs & negatives; Contents of envelopes, Undated (Volume 15)
  - Alphabetized list of negatives, Undated (Volume 23)